Contact

6376840832 (Mobile) mailharshkhatri@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ harshkumarkhatri (LinkedIn) harshkumarkhatri.github.io/ Portfolio-Site/dist/index.html (Portfolio) medium.com/@mailharshkhatri (Blog)

Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Flutter

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Languages

Sindhi (Professional Working)
English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Full Professional)

Certifications

Using Python to Interact with the Operating System

Python 3 Programming Specialization

Python Data Structures

Python Classes and Inheritance Introduction to Git and GitHub

Honors-Awards

Microsoft Student Partners 2020-21 Google IT Automation Professional Certificate Badge

Harsh kumar Khatri

Google DSC Lead | Microsoft Students Learn Ambassador | deeplearning.ai event Ambassador | Mentor- HackItShipIt(MLH), HakinCodes, H4TP | IncubateIND Fellow | Coding Ninja Campus Expert | Team lead at VOC | ISP-16,17

Summary

Elon Musk once said "Persistence is very important. You should not give up unless you are forced to give up."

As a to be Software Developer who converts code into software and applications to provide an experience for the users, I live by this motto.

I am currently a CSE undergraduate from Career Point University, Kota, who keep exploring and learning new things to level up my skills and contribute back to the community in any way possible. My goto programming languages are Python and Flutter.

I also make content related to things that I learn or problems that I face to help others who face similar problems. Youtube:- http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCKNtMU9M559bmXxKoT6YeJw Blog:-https://medium.com/@mailharshkhatri.

I am focused on helping out the people of the community and beyond such that we, as a community, work together on real-world problems and make an impact.

With excellent communication skills, I am also a great team player and a self-starter who likes to engage in a logical thinking approach to problem-solving.

When I am not coding you can find me chilling out with friends or scrolling through the web.

Experience

Developer Student Clubs

Google DSC Lead

August 2020 - Present (1 month)

I have always enjoyed learning from GDEs and Leads at Google.

I am hoping to create an impact on students through technology by introducing them to communities at an early age.

I will be updating this once I complete my journey as a DSC lead.

Microsoft

5 months

Microsoft Student Learn Ambassadors

August 2020 - Present (1 month)

Microsoft Students Partner

April 2020 - August 2020 (5 months)

Microsoft Student Partner is one of those communities which has helped me grow as an individual in personal as well as professional life. I got to learn so much from people all around the globe.

I also organized multiple tech events and was a speaker at a few of such events which enhanced my presenting and problem-solving skills.

Microsoft Student Partner is rebranded to Microsoft Student Learn Ambassadors.

HakinCodes

Mentor

August 2020 - Present (1 month)

This is an awesome opportunity provided to me by the HakinCodes team through which I would be able to mentor and guide people from a different technology background and be a part of the opensource community on a larger scale. Along with this, it is the best chance to showcase my skills as well and influence young minds who are a part of this hackathon.

Incubate IND

Fellow

July 2020 - Present (2 months)

This is a 60-day program that is offered by Incubate IND for personal and professional growth.

deeplearning.ai

Event Ambassador

June 2020 - Present (3 months)

I was appointed as a deeplearning.ai event ambassador on 25th June 2020. The responsibilities of an event ambassador are to organize and conduct events related to artificial intelligence and machine learning every month. Till now I have conducted an event, prior to being appointed as an event ambassador, for deeplearning.ai which was around the theme of Introduction to ML & Al.

You can find me on the map on https://www.deeplearning.ai/events/ in Kota, India

Voice of Code Management Team lead May 2020 - Present (4 months)

Voice of Code is a blogging community started by Microsoft student partner community members to educate people around the globe with good content related to technical and non-technical fields.

Coding Ninjas India Campus Ambassador February 2020 - Present (7 months) Kota Area, India

Learn4exam
Campus Ambassador
February 2020 - Present (7 months)

Humanity Welfare Council Campus Ambassador January 2020 - Present (8 months)

Hack for the People
Hackathon Mentor
August 2020 - August 2020 (1 month)

Hack For The People was an intercollegiate hackathon designed to engage students in tackling some of the world's largest problems. From issues in the economy to trying to channel people's inner patriotism, the sky's the limit.

I got a chance to be a mentor and guide the participants such that they end up making good things and have an overall learning experience.

Major League Hacking

Mentor-HackItShipIt
July 2020 - July 2020 (1 month)

HackItShipIt was a part of the brand new summer hackathon league series which is organized by Major League Hacking and in this series, a hackathon is conducted every weekend.

I got a chance to be a mentor at HackItShipIt, which was a two-day hackathon, and this was a hell of an experience. I got to have a conversation with people from various different subcontinent and solve their doubts which made me learn and research new things. The MLH team was also great and was there to help mentors and participants. This was a change for me as well as I have always been a participant at a hackathon prior to this and now after being a mentor I got to know what all things are going there under the hood.

INNOVA DTU

Campus Ambassador February 2020 - May 2020 (4 months)

It was a good opportunity to work here and learn about new things.

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Allahabad Campus Ambassador February 2020 - May 2020 (4 months)

This was a type of internship which i got through internshala. In it i had to promote the technical fest which was there to take place in IIIT, Allahabad.

Internshala ISP-16 December 2019 - May 2020 (6 months) work from home

This was a great learning opportunity provided by the internshala team. With the help of this initiative i was able to host sessions and make people aware about the technology trends

Education

Career Point University Kota

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science · (2018 - 2022)

St. Paul's Sen. Sec. School, Kota 12th, Science (2016 - 2018)

St. Paul's Sen. Sec. School, Kota 10th · (2007 - 2016)

Hacker Rank
Computer Programming